# GUSTAVO PEREIRA

## FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

gustavopereira.co.uk



guhenriques



guhenriques-1398



guhenriques1398@gmail.com



0742340-1232



London

Right to work: Spouse Visa

#### SKILLS

#### Front-end:

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- · jQuery, React

#### Back-end:

- PHP
- Node.js
- Express
- SQL
- MongoDB
- REST API

#### DevOps:

- Git & GitHub
- Swagger
- Docker

### LANGUAGES

- English
- Portuguese
- Spanish

#### EDUCATION

Systems Development & Analysis University Estacio de Sa -Sao Paulo, Brazil

2020-2022

#### PROFILE

I have several years of customer service experience and dedicated 2 years to coordinating a Minecraft Server Project. During this time, I discovered a genuine interest in programming and development.

Recently, I completed a coding traineeship as a full stack developer, completing two real-world projects to specification using a diverse set of programming languages.

Enthusiastic about pursuing my passion, I am eager to forge a career in the development field where I can showcase my skills as a valuable asset.

### CODING TRAINEESHIP

# Full Stack Developer - 1 year program IT Career Switch

Jul 2022 - Jul 2023

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills:

- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript
- PHP, SQL, React, jQuery
- Python, Node.js, Express
- Git, GitHub
- REST API.

Below are the two briefs of development projects I completed with IT Career Switch, which can be found in my bio: https://gustavopereira.co.uk/

## Portfolio Project #1 - "Gazetteer"

• The task was to respond to a website specification for a map-based app designed to offer information about various countries, with a strong emphasis on "mobile-first" development. It was recommended to employ a framework for this purpose, followed by the creation of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript with jQuery modules. These modules would then utilize PHP server-based components to fetch data from third-party APIs. The evaluation of the solution would be based on its adherence to the specifications, functionality, and user-friendliness.

## Portfolio Project #2 - "Company Directory"

A more rigorous reply to this specification was required as a user requirements
document was needed to be prepared which, when signed off, triggers the release
of SQL allowing to develop a "mobile-first" application to maintain a company
personnel database (MySQL). Sign off is only achieved upon the student supplying
an independently witnessed document providing confirmation of the system's
ability to perform error-free.

#### WORK HISTORY

## Web Developer Volunteer Amnick Social Enterprise

Oct 2023 - Present

- Collaborating with a team of developers to rebuild company websites exclusively using WordPress.
- Assisting with content migration.
- Focused on creating responsive and mobile-friendly designs while working closely with other developers to meet the company's WordPress requirement
- Providing basic SEO optimization.

#### **Bar Staff**

#### JD Wetherspoon

Sep 2023 - Present

- · Providing friendly and efficient customer service.
- Preparing and serve beverages following company standards.
- Handling cash transactions and maintain a clean bar area.
- Ensuring compliance with alcohol service regulations.
- Collaborating with the team for smooth operation.

#### **Customer Assistant**

#### **Tesco Stores**

Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

- · Assisted customers on the shop floor
- Restocked shop items and maintained an organised and tidy shop floor
- · Managed the in-store bakery
- · Received customers at checkout tills and provided assistance with self-checkouts

## Guest Services Agent Grand Hyatt Hotel São Paulo

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

- Answered incoming calls promptly and professionally, providing information about hotel services, amenities, and others
- Received and processed guest requests, such as wake-up calls, room service orders, and transportation arrangements
- Responded to guest complaints or concerns and resolved issues promptly and effectively to ensure guest satisfaction
- Demonstrated and promoted a strong commitment to providing the best possible experience for both guests and employees

### **CEO**

#### **MundoMinecraft Brasil**

Jan 2018 - Apr 2020

- Led a Minecraft Server project with 200 average concurrent players, collaborating with a team of software engineers
- Modified Java-based plugins to add new features and fix issues
- Managed server operations using PUTTY and SSL on Linux
- Collaborated with team members to implement new features and maintain server stability
- Assisted in the development and customisation of the WordPress e-commerce platform for in-game purchases and real toy products

## WORK HISTORY - 2

# Front Office Team Leader Estanplaza Berrini Hotel

Sep 2018 - Aug 2021

- Oversaw the day-to-day operations of the front desk and ensured a smooth check-in and check-out process for guests
- Monitored the performance of front desk staff, conducted regular evaluations, and provided feedback for improvement
- Created shift schedules for the front desk team and ensured adequate coverage during peak times
- Enforced hotel policies and procedures to maintain high-quality standards and compliance with safety and security regulations

## Front Office Assistant Estanplaza Berrini Hotel

Mar 2018 - Sep 2018

- Assisted guests with the check-in process, verified identification, and processed payments during check-out
- Managed room bookings, ensured accuracy, and addressed any reservation-related inquiries
- Furnished guests with information about hotel amenities, services, local attractions, and directions

## Bellboy Estanplaza Berrini Hotel

Jul 2017 - Feb 2018

- Greeted guests upon arrival, helping them with their luggage, and escorting them to their rooms
- Ensured that guests' needs and requests were promptly addressed with a courteous and helpful attitude
- Arranged taxis or other transportation services for guests upon request
- Supported the front desk team during busy periods or when additional assistance was required